We live in the village I have a toilet
Мы живём в деревне у меня есть унитаз у
I have My friend has a toilet other
меня У моего друга есть унитаз у других
friends of mine can you show I have
друзей моих униз можешь показать Я
never seen that in Irkutsk Land there
никогда не видел что в Иркутске Ланд
were toilets ud there were toilets And you
были унитазы уд были унитазы А вы меня
excuse me of course but look we are in
извините конечно но смотрите мы в
the village we have We are now sitting in Zimovye
деревне у нас у Мы сейчас в Зимовье
we are now just in Zimovye
сидим просто мы сейчас просто в Зимовье
Yes we are sitting we well we can show
Да сидим у нас ну мы можем показать
Just I can show live Show
Просто я могу показать пожи Покажите
wait Show you
подожди
can show him where the toilet
Покажи можешь показать ему где унитаз
dates camera And here yes camera while Now
даты камеру А вот да камера пока Сейчас
wait now
подождите сейчас
wait we just have now night
подождите у нас просто сейчас ночь
Yeah quiet bud
Ага тихо буд
Bau Well
Бау Ну вот
look here and he works there is water
смотрите вот а он рабо это там вода есть
in m
в м
or hello let's talk noma let's
или здравствуйте давайте поговорим нома
talk let's I am from the city of Khmelnitsky where are
поговорим давай я из города Хмельницкий
you from where are you from we are from Russia we we are from
вы откуда вы откуда мы с России мы мы с
Russia from the Irkutsk region Here I saw
России с Иркутской области Вот я я видел
that Russia by the curtains I'm just wondering
что Россия по шторам просто интересно
Which region is Irkutsk Which region is Irkutsk
Какая область Иркутская Какая область
Yes
Иркутская Да
Irkutsk 138 region how far is it from
Иркутская 138 регион как далеко от
Irkutsk How far is it from Irkutsk yes yes not
Иркутска Как далеко от Иркутска да да не
we in  Irkutsk is about 3 km away No, you are in
мы в Иркутске 3 км примерно Не ну вы в
some Well, you live in a village, I
каком-то Ну вы в деревне живёте я
understand, yes, in a village, in a
понимаю да да в посёлке в посёлке м
village, I understand, that is, you live there, well,
посёлке понял то есть живёте там ну как
not as rich as in Moscow, rich as in
бы не так богато как в Москве богато как
Moscow, no, but we live well Wait,
в Москве не но не мы доста живём Подожди
wait, we are not rich, at least we live Well, we
подожди мы не богато хоть живёт Ну мы
live normally, in abundance,
при Ну нормально так живём в достатке
as if I understood everything, but in abundance Well, they
как бы все понял а в достатке Ну нам
just show us on TV that
просто показывают по телевизорам что у
you have toilets in Moscow And
вас вот в Москве есть унитазы Да и
washing machines, and already Buryatia, the
стиральные машины а уже Бурятия
Trans-Baikal Territory, the Irkutsk region,
Забайкальский край Иркутская области
there is no Krai, the Irkutsk region, I have
нету кра Иркутская области нету
no We live in a village, I
у меня у меня Мы живём в деревне у меня
have a toilet, I have a friend,
есть унитаз у меня У моего друга есть
other friends have a toilet, mo, can you
унитаз у других друзей мо можешь
show me I have never seen that in
показать Я никогда не видел что в
Irkutsk, Lana had a toilet,
Иркутске Лану были унитаз
excuse me, of course, but
униз вы меня извините конечно но
look, we are in a village, we are We are now
смотрите мы в деревне у нас Мы сейчас в
sitting in Zimovye, just now we are about in
Зимовье сидим просто мы сейчас про в
Zimovye Yes, we are sitting, we can show I can
Зимовье Да Сидим мы можем
show you can Show him where,
показать можеш Показать ему где
but here  ses now now wait now
а вот сес сейчас сейчас подождите сейчас
wait we just have now night Yeah
подождите у нас просто сейчас ночь Ага
yeah oh quiet be grandma
ага во тихо будь бабушка
[music]
[музыка]
with Well
с Ну вот
look here a and it works well is there
смотрите вот а а он работат ну это там
water in it or is it a model there is or a
вода есть в нём или это макет есть или
model No of course there is So where where to
макет Нет конечно есть Так а где где
drain no
сливать нету
sva Cool
свать Прикольно
normally really Yes there is
нормально действительно Да есть
really Yes there is And what did you say
действительно Да есть А что вы говорили
that you are in Zimovye this is
что вы в Зимовье это
like well we are in Zimov just relaxing And what
как ну мы в Зимов просто отдыхаем А что
is a zimovye what is
такое зимовьё чтов
it like a house but it is a place here it is just
это как бы дом но он поме вот он просто
smaller like also there is a stove
поменьше типа также печка
go figure you know this is how can you
поди зи это знаете такое как бы вам
embrace this this is a house for relaxation like
такое объять это дом для отдыха типа
separately from the
отдельно вот от
house that is it turns out that in the summer you
дома то есть получается что летом вы в
live in the house And in the winter when it is cold
доме живёте А зимой когда холод во
this is a house purely for relaxation it is just
это дом чисто так для отдыха он просто
for relaxation yes yes for relaxation Well like a dacha
для отдыха да да для отдыха Ну как дача
there is everything else That is to say this is
там все остальное Вот то есть вот это у
your house for relaxation with such a stove yes a
вас дом для отдыха с печкой такой да
stove yes yes for relaxation it is purely
печко такой да да да для отдыха он чисто
for relaxation good And I thought but is
так для отдыха хорошо А я думал а такой
n't such a house for relaxation isn't it for
дом разве не для отдыха разве не для
relaxation no no they just live in such a house
отдыха не не просто в таком доме просто
Don't look funny Look
живут Не смотрите прикол Вот смотрите
how  how how to explain it to you like this
как как как вам так объяснить Типа так
in a smart way
вот по умному
here is winter it is like for those people Well
вот зима он как бы для тех людей Ну
Slav here is a language on us yes ve Slavyan it is
славянин вот язна на нас да ве славян он
for for those who live in winter And now it is
для для тех кто зимой живёт А сейчас он
like time there yes Here has come
как бы время там да Вот пришло вот это
this long there yes Well with time Yes this
вот долго там да Ну со временем Да это
is already an ordinary house has come well winter quarters
вот уже обычный дом пришёл ну зимовьё
that's all an ordinary house has appeared
вот все дела обычный дом появился вот
like where they can already live peacefully Well
типа где уже жить могут уже спокойно Вот
with a toilet and all that And this house in
с унитазом все дела А вот этот вот дом в
which we are sitting now this is an
котором мы сейчас сидим вот это вот да
ordinary
обычный
winter quarters there is nothing special in it Well there
зимовьё в нём ничего такого Ну
is no modern not
современного нету
it just like that well sit and rest you
не он просто так вот ну сидеть отдыхать
can say just like that rest and that's it
можно сказать просто так отдыхать и всё
Well as if settled down like that old
Ну как бы остепенился вот такую старую
old time Here you can say and
старое время Вот можно сказать а
retrospective such iri retrospective
ретроспектива такая ири ретроспектива
such hysterical just like a house only
такая истерическая так же как дом только
smaller Well drink well those who want this
поменьше Ну ипей ну те кто хочет это вот
in this nostalgia here to cover I understood that
в эту вот ностальгию вот накрыть я понял
you are here for the sake of nostalgia
то есть вы сюда за ради ностальгии
Come like that Come that Yes yes we we are
Приходите так Приходите того Да да мы мы
lovers of antiquity You probably still
любители старины У вас наверное там ещё
have Soviet records there
грампластинки есть там советские
to play a gramophone  this is no longer the case
поиграть патифон это уже этого уже нету
we don't have this of course it hasn't
не у нас такого не конечно не
survived because we are like people from
сохранилось потому что мы как бы люди с
20 well 20 we are 20 years old Of course we have
20 ну 20 нам по 20 лет Конечно нам
n't survived
такого не сохранилось Конечно
this Of course I understand And what do you do for a living what
вот понял А кем вы работаете кем вы
do you do for a living we go to the north Yes we
работаете мы ездим на мы севера Да на
work normally on shifts we
вахтах работаем нормально так прилично
earn decently and quietly
зарабатываем спокойно
but it turns out that's where you
а получается вот вы куда вы деньги
spend your money in the north In the north Well look
девает на севере На севере Ну смотри
some money can be
некоторые деньги можно в
spent on domras we earn money Yes in the house
домры деньги мы зарабатываем Да в Дом
there well well whoever wants I for example
там ну ну кто куда хочет я вот например
I have a house and all the things I well my own
у меня дом есть все дела Я вот ну свои
things
дела
my car took He also took a car
мо машину взял Он тоже машину
when we can and m Well we can
кода можем и м есть Ну можем дом там
improve the house there or the car there well well all the
улучшить там или машину там ну ну все
things In short all the things And what kind of cars did
дела Короче все дела А какие Тачки себе
you take for yourself how did you take the GAZ 24
взяли ка тебе взяли ГАЗ 24
Volga Well I took it I took it I took it they Well you
Волга Ну я взял я взял я взял они Ну Вы
look they are expensive now they are now Yes they are expensive
посмотрите они дорогие сейчас они сейчас
they are now yes
Да они дорогие они сейчас да
attractive cars Well this is purely my
привлекательные машины Ну это чисто моё
opinion I would like to take the GAZ 24 Volga
мнение Я как бы я взял вот ГАЗ 24 Волга
you
вы
know the Volga
знаете Волгу
I had a dream to take such a car
у меня мечта была такая машину взять
my grandfather had one  My
такую у меня дед на такой ездил у меня
father drove one like this I want to get one
отец на такой ездил Я хочу такую взять
too But I forgot Are you lovers of antiquity do
тоже А я же забыл Вы любители старины у
you have this retrospective vision
вас это ретроспективное зрение
yes switched off such some kind of
да отключились такие
mattress Where are you from
матрасный какой-то Вы откуда Россия
Russia Russia city What city
России город Какой город
Magadan Sunny
Магадан Солнечный
Magadan For whom it is different For you
Магадан Для кого как Для вас
like Sunny
как Солнечный
Magadan somehow in a white shirt straight generally
Магадан как-то в белой рубашке пря вобще
solemn Yes I am a teacher at
торжественно Да я Преподаватель
the University of America in
университета Америке в
Sacramento Yeah because Well for some reason
Сакраменто Угу потому что Ну почему-то у
I probably have this VPN Yes here is VPN I
меня это ВПН наверное стоит Да вот VPN Я
put it because if I put America
ставлю потому что если я ставлю Америка
I don't get Ukraine and Russia when
мне не попадается Украина и Россия когда
I put Ukraine then I get Ukrainians And
я ставлю Украину мне тогда и украинцы И
Russians You
россияне
clearly understand how it is
попадаются Ясно понимаете как там
Sacramento is normal listen Question is
Сакраменто нормально слушайте Вопрос
how is it for you because of the war in Magadan has
такой как там вам из-за войны в Магадане
life started to get better or worse damn
лучше началось жить или хуже
much better industry has started to
блин гораздо лучше промышленность стала
develop what has
развиваться что у вас
developed your military industry what do
развилось военная промышленность что у
you have in Magadan
вас в Магадане
Elk tell you specifically factories some
Лось вам конкретно заводы сказать
numbers or something what have you
какие-то номера какие-то ли что ва у вас
got more cars more oil How did you
стало больше машин больше масла Как вы
start to
стали лучше
live better a job
жить работа
appeared in Magadan Are
появилась в Магадане
you working now And how much
Вы сейчас работаете И сколько
do you get I work
получаете Я работаю на Карном санке
I get 85,000
получаю 85.000
rubles on the Karny Sank That is, you get 800 dollars in Magadan
руб То есть ты в Магадане получаешь 800
Yes, you Ask how much I pay for
Да вы Спросите сколько я плачу за
utilities
коммунальные услуги
again Look, this is not a joke, you
ещё раз Смотри это это это не анекдот ты
really live in Magadan and in this
реально живёшь в Магадане и в этой
permafrost you get paid to work at the machine
мерзлоте получаешь за станком работаешь
and get 800 dollars
и получаешь 800 долларов
Yes,
да
yes, in
да в
Magadan, in this I pay for
Магадане в этом плачу за коммунальные
utilities 50
услуги 50
dollars for
долларов за
electricity, for gas, for garbage collection,
электроэнергию за газ за вывоз мусора я
I pay 50 50 dollars and for cherries
я плачу 50 50 долларов а за черешню
How much do you
Сколько ты
pay what kind of cherries per kilogram of
платишь какую черешню за килограмм
cherries For example, I dont Eat cherries We
черешни Например я не Кушу черешню У нас
have our own berries per kilo, our own
есть своя ягода за кило своя своя
cherries in this in
черешня в этом в
Magadan, our own berries, berries, I understand how much
Магадане своя ягода ягода понял сколько
tomatoes cost in
помидоры у вас стоят в
Magadan, we have a greenhouse,
Магадане у нас теплица
that is, in Magadan, a greenhouse with
есть то есть в Магадане теплица с
tomatoes, you have
помидорами у вас
Yes, how much do you pay for utilities
Да сколько вы платите за коммунальные
for a question, a question, we call it a
за вопрос вопрос вопрос у нас это
greenhouse in
теплица в
Magadan,
Магадане
tomatoes, oranges, there are no
помидоры апельсины там не
grow everything how much is your
выращиваете всё сколько у вас
temperature now in Magadan wait
температура сейчас в Магадане подождите
wait everything from laughing how much is your
подождите всё от смеялись сколько у вас
temperature now wait wait
сейчас температура подожди подожди
wait
подожди
I'll ask a question how much do you pay for
я задам вопрос сколько вы платите за
utilities where in what state in the
коммунальные услуги где в каком штате в
state of Sacramento look I have a
штате Сакраменто смотрите У меня
salary like a simple teacher
зарплата как у простого преподавателя
9,000 dollars Yes no no no I asked
9.000 долларов Да нет нет нет я спросил
Question how much do you pay for
Вопрос сколько вы платите за
utilities I I pay 100
коммунальные услуги я я плачу 100
dollars for all utilities and
долларов за все коммунальные услуги и у
I have 8,900 dollars left
меня остаётся 8.900 долларов
10 ssya you pay and you have 88,000
10 сся вы платите и у Вас остаётся 88000
dollars left I pay 100 100 dollars I pay
долларов я плачу 100 100 долларов плачу
Look my salary is in Russian rubles
Смотри у меня зарплата на русские рубли
900,000 I didn't ask your salary I'm
900.000 Я не спрашивал вашу зарплату Я
saying I'll pay only
говорю у меня оплачу всего
10,000 rubles commune rubles you pay
10.000 рублей комуна руб вы платите за
dollars for utilities Where did you come from
долларов Откуда такой взялся
you I communicated in Europe before you in
ты ты я до тебя общался в Европе в
Europe I communicated before you and there the price was
Европе я общался до тебя и там цена была
much higher And you, uncle,
гораздо больше А ты дядька
how much did the
сколько порвался
narrow one break how much  communal Tell me how much do
узкий сколько коммуналка Скажи сколько у
you have now I'm parodying ka
тебя сейчас я с пародирую ка
look tell me
смотри скажи
How much do you have
Сколько у тебя
communal
коммуналка
Hello Hello What are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Что вы
eating Damn just had
кушаете Блин только
a bite what did you have a bite
закусил что закусил
sorry got into trouble So this is well okay
извините попал Так что это ну ладно
now prozh prozh
сейчас прож прож
Where are you from What
Вы откуда Из какого
city am I from Russia Yes I can see by your face
города Я из России Да это я вижу по лицу
what city by your face or Why do you see
какой по лицу или Почему вы видите по
by your face I see And what is Russian so immediately you can see right away firstly secondly A yes Well you are sitting with an American flag everything is fine with you Yes everything is fine with me yes Well done And the third one is a toothless
Молодцы какие А ещё третий это без зубо
face Yes you have this you know
лицо Да вот у вас такое вот знаеш
insulting a person I don't know you
оскорблять человека не знаю у вас вот
you are just high yes high high really T
вас прёт прямо да прёт прёт реально Т
Yes it means what should be done with you
Да значит вас что с вами надо делать а
but if you are so high this
вот если вас так прёт вот это вот
American What should be done with you The point is that
американская Что с вами надо
you can't do anything
делать Суть в том что вы ничего не
howl in what you imagine we can
выть в том что представляешь сможем
do in the coming
сделать в ближайшие
years in the coming years we will do what we
годы ближайшие годы сделаем что
will do we will do Well what what should we
сделаете сделаем Ну что что
clean up this whole your
зачистить вот эту всю вашу
measure what
промерить какого
city from Kaliningrad with That's just
города с Калининграда с Вот как раз как
exactly your
раз вашу
your your soon  clean up
вашу вашу скоро очистят в Калининграде
all yours in Kaliningrad They will clean it up soon, yes, let them
всю вашу Скоро очистят это да пускай
try, let them try, for example,
попытаются давай Пускай пыта например
the Finns took a Russian ship, arrested it, and
фины взяли российское судно арестовали и
what could Russia do,
что Россия смогла сделать
here are some of those stories for you, shows, But
ничего вот вам такие истории показы А
somewhere they heard something about Russia,
вот где-то что-то услышали про Россию
and let's develop the topic, No, it's
что-то и давай развивать тему Не ну
true, they boarded it, took the ship
правда ж забрали на абордаж взяли судно
like
как
Pirates, Okay, let's do it,
Пираты Хорошо давай
And the fact that the Americans have already sold out your
так А то что [__] Уже продали вашу
Ukraine, Yes, I'm not from Ukraine, I come from
Украину Да я не из Украины я родом из
Rostov, I just live in America, 18 years old, in
Ростова просто живу в Америке 18 лет в
California, in 2 years, it will be
Калифорнии через 2 года будет
twenty, the guy, that's because I'm
двадцатки парень-то пото потому что я
already a citizen of the United States of America,
уже гражданин Соединённых Штатов Америки
a great
Великой
country, Yes, there are two great countries,
страны Да есть две великие страны
two, no, three, three, name it,
две нет Три три назови
no, four, four great countries, Let's call
нет четыре четыре великие стра Давай
America
называй Америка
that way,
так
Russia, China and India, These are four
Россия Китай и Индия Вот это четыре
great countries, a great country is
великие страны великая страна - это
America, Russia is not great, they
Америка Россия не великая на Россию
attacked Russia, Sudzha, the Kursk region, it
напали на суджу на курскую область она
cannot recapture the Kursk region,
не может курскую область отвоевать
America, if someone drank even a
Америка если бы кто-то хоть пил на
centimeter of American territory, he would
сантиметр американской территории и он
be turned into powder, sulfuric Ash  And
был бы в порошок сёр вный Пепел А вы вас
nobody is afraid of you, so I went to the USA and
никто не боится поэтому я поехал в США
got a passport of a Great Power, a
стал получил паспорт Великой державы
really Great Power that everyone
действительно Великой которую все
was afraid of. And I also have a passport of a Great
боялись А у меня паспорт тоже Великой
Power, and I
державы и я вот
would be sitting here with you at the
вот сидел бы я сейчас с тобой за
table right now. I would hit you on the head like that. Look,
столом Вот так по башке тебе
you are a great country. First get your
бы Смотри ты великая страна Ты сначала
teeth done. In a Great country, why is
зубы себе сделай в Великой стране Почему
everyone
в Великой стране все
toothless in a Great country? Why is everyone toothless in your Great country?
беззубые Почему в вашей Великой стране
Explain that in our Great country.
объясни что в нашей Великой стране
Why is everyone toothless in your Great country?
Почему в вашей Великой стране все
This is a tradition.
беззубые это Традиция
What is so nice? Understand. Well, be without it.
такая В чём Ница Поня Да ну быть безу
If we didnt have
если бы не были
a [ __ ], we wouldnt be. We wouldnt
пизду мы бы не были мы бы никому не
give it to anyone. If we all had
давали бы если бы были все с
teeth, but now we give everything. We give everything. And the whole
зубами а сейчас все даём даём все И весь
world.
мир
And what did
А что
you eat? Who knocked out your teeth? You
съел кто вам выбил зубы
understand that with people like that, and
вот с такими это понимаешь а зубы
my interlocutors teeth flew out. He
полетели у моего собеседника ещё больше
doesnt have any more.
их нету
Imagine thats how it is in Russia. If
представляет вот так у нас в России если
we fight, it means we knock out teeth completely. Well, we leave a little
бьёмся значит выбиваем зубы до конца Ну
bit for ourselves. We
себе чуть-чуть оставляем оставляем Ну
leave. Well, I understand that, and why dont you put the knocked-out teeth back in? Okay, we fought, got carried away, knocked out, the time hasnt come.  The
погорячились выбили время не пришло
time will come, we insert, we insert, how much
Придёт время вставляем вставляем сколько
time has passed with your teeth knocked out,
у вас уже прошло времени с выбитыми
I've been walking for a year, Well, I
зубами я годик хожу Ну
walk, go, walk with such a dude, yes, Well, yes, I
хожу го ходите с такой челю да Ну да
pulled out,
вырвал
pulled out, they hurt, pulled out, And now I'll
вырвал болели вырвал А сейчас буду
insert km, you work, young
вставлять км работаете молодой
man, I work, I work normally as a
человек я работаю Я нормально работаю
driver, I work as a driver,
водителем работаю водителем
what kind of
чего
car,
автомобиля
what kind,
какого какого
Well,
Ну
a truck, how much is your
грузового сколько у вас
salary, our salary is
зарплата у нас зарплата
70,000 rubles, that is, 700 dollars, And it
70.000 руб то есть 700 долларов Да и мне
seems to me that you will never get your teeth inserted, Well,
кажется что вы зубы не вставить
I'll tell you, but we have 700 dollars, if,
я вам скажу но у нас 700 долларов если
Well, you basically said it right, 700
Ну да ты в принципе правильно сказал 700
dollars, we don't
долларов мы не
count, we never convert to dollars,
считаем не переводим никогда в доллары
Well, rubles are normal for us, This is our currency,
Ну у нас рубли нормально Это наша валюта
as they say,
Как говорится
normal, Well, I'll tell you
нормально Ну я тебе вот скажу
why I won't insert
что почему я не вставлю
20,000 rubles for 200 dollars, what are you,
20.000 руб за 200 долларов что ты
how many
сколько у тебя
teeth are
зубов не
missing, two, two, You want to say that
хватает два два Ты хочешь сказать что по
they put in for you at 100 dollars per tooth,
100 долларов за зуб ставят
No, I'm saying that
тебе Нет я говорю что
20 thousand,
20 тысяч
one tooth, 200 dollars, it turns out,
зуб один зуб 200 долларов получается
yeah, wait
да подожди
20,000 on  100
20.000 на 100
divided will be
Разделить будет
200 it turns out yes 200 dollars or not it
200 получается да 200 долларов или не
seems 2000 if 20,000 divided by 100
вроде 2000 если 20.000 разделить на 100
will be
будет
2,000 2,000 dollars is already
2.000 2.000 долларов это уже
a lot you yourself have confused me now not this
много ты сам меня сечас запутал не это
you have confused 200000
ты запутал 200000
yes it's simple mathematics Look yes
да это же простая математика Смотри да
you forgot me at first 20,000 divided by
ты меня сначала забыла 20.000 делим на
100 turns out 200 dollars well 200
100 получается 200 долларов ну 200
dollars per tooth Yes Oh 2,000 dollars Not
долларов за зуб Да Ой 2.000 долларов Не
again look 20,000 divided by 100
ещё раз смотри 20.000 делим на 100
turns out not No no no not 2,000
получается не Нет нет нет не 2.000
2,000 look you now yourself You yourself have already
2.000 смотри ты сейчас сам Ты сам уже
confused 20,000 We take 2 zeros there
запутался 20.000 Забираем 2 нуля
remains a two and 3 zeros 2,000 dollars
остаётся двойка и 3 нуля 2.000 долларов
2,000 dollars per tooth where do you put such
2.000 долларов за зуб где ты такой
wait 20 20,000 rubles rubles If I
подожди 20 20.000 руб рублей Если я
get 8  70,000 rubles what should I put in Well,
получаю 8 70.000 руб что мне ставить Ну
I'll spend half my salary on two teeth
я потрачу пол зарплаты на два зуба
okay question if if if it
хорошо вопрос если если если вставить
costs 20 dollars to put in a tooth E 200 dollars yes then
зуб стоит 20 долла Э 200 долларов да то
what kind of tooth do they put in for you there wooden
какой тебе зуб там ставят деревянный
plastic iron Which is
пластмассовый железный Какой нормальный
normal normal for 200
нормально за 200
dollars and what is this is not enough or what it
долларов а что это это мало что ли там
seems to be
вроде
not enough Well, our prices are different you understand you
мало Ну у нас цены другие понимаешь ты
live in America You let's say this
вот живёшь в Америке Ты это давай так
How much do you pay for
Сколько ты платишь за коммунальные
utilities 5
услуги 5
dollars only yes 5 dollars You
долларов всего лишь да 5 долларов Ты
pay yes
платишь да
We have heat we don't use
У нас тепло у нас газ не используется
gas we have electricity Solar
электричество у нас Солнечная
power plant on the house Only a factory
электростанция на доме Только завод
In short, you don't live Okay 5 dollars No
Короче вы на живёте Ладно 5 долларов Не
well 5 dollars and you How much do you pay I 500
ну 5 долларов а ты Сколько платишь я 500
rubles And you
руб А ты
how much will I
сколько я тебе
tell you No come on honestly already honestly I'm
скажу Нет давай честно уже чест я те
honest look we have gas in California
чест смотри газа у нас в Калифорнии газа
No gas We have heat we have completely we have
Нет Во У нас тепло у нас полностью у нас
no winter cold we don't use
зимы нету холода у нас газ не использу
gas all the electricity is from solar
электрика вся от солнечны
batteries In what
батаре В каком
ye understand in what
те понимаю в каком
sh California then you How much do you pay for
ш Калифорния то ты Сколько платишь за
utilities I'll tell you the truth now  I'll
коммуналку я тебе правду сейчас
tell you right now for December
скажу вот сейчас за декабрь
I paid 9000 rubles 90 dollars
заплатил 9000 руб 90 долларов
yes that
да то есть
means your salary is
получается у тебя зарплата
70,000 And you paid 9000 you
70.000 А ты 9000 ты
1/8 1/8 of the salary somewhere 12 percent
1/8 1/8 зарплаты 12 где-то процентов
for utilities Yes this is crazy
заплатил за коммуналку Да это жесть Боже
My God that I would pay 90
мой чтобы я в Калифорнии платил 90
dollars for utilities in California this is crazy
долларов за коммуналку это жесть
some kind of
какой-то
nonsense so far But I'm for this
бред ещ пока это Но я зати это
four-room apartment So I have a house I have a
четырёхкомнатную квартиру Так я за дом у
two-story house
двухэтажный
rooms I have a two-story house in which
комнаты У меня двухэтажный дом в котором
de rooms
де комнат
de I have look 5 dollars for
де у меня смотри 5 долларов за
de
де у
you have a multi-story house 5 dollars for utilities per
тебя этажный дом 5 долларов коммуналка в
month per room
месяц за комнат
de For now show show that you have four
де Пока покажи покажи что у тебя четыре
rooms I don't believe it no I'm at the dacha now
комнаты не верю не я сейчас на даче
I can't do
нахожусь я не могу
it right away I
те сразу Я те я тебе клянусь я тебе
swear to you I swear to you I'm telling you honestly I'm at the
клянусь я честно тебе говорю я сейчас на
dacha now I'm sitting drinking
даче я сижу бухаю
here at the dacha I can show you the dacha I'm
вот на даче могу показать тебе дачу
sitting in my kitchen so why do you all
у себя на кухне сижу вот а почему вы все
leave alone to drink on
уезжаете в одиночку бухать на
dacha Why do we
даче Почему мы
leave we have a
уезжаем мы
normal rest because we have an
нормально Отдыхаем потому что у нас есть
apartment in the city and a dacha
квартира в городе и дача
a little bit outside the city
есть немножко загородом
we can grill shashlik here
мы можем здесь и шашлычок пожарить
everything This is my territory I can
всё Это моя территория я могу всё что
do everything that I want here That is, you
здесь что хочу здесь сделать То есть ты
can even take it in the middle of the room
взять даже даже можешь посреди комнаты
yes yes go out
да да выйти вот
even here This is my territory you
даже вот здесь Это моя территория
understand
понимаешь
I cleaned it up today tomorrow it's
Я сегодня завтра
mine it's my property
убрал это моё моё это моя собственность
like that
вот так
and you tell me life in Russia
вот а ты мне говоришь жизнь в России
Yes life in Russia and your America here
Да жизнь в России и твоя Америка здесь
were not even
вообще не стояла
close and what's the trick today clean up
рядом а в чём фишка сегодня убрать
tomorrow Well I can
завтра Ну могу сразу же
clean up right away Well look I don't believe that you can
убрать Ну смотри я не верю что ты можешь
take and here on your territory it's
взять и вот у себя на территории это
impossible It's not yours No I just tell you Well
невозможно Это не твоя Нет я просто тебе
just take it and show what you
Ну просто возьми возьми и Покажи что ты
can do to you what to go or what Yes yes yes yes
можешь тебе что пойти что ли Да да да да
yes
да
even for your
ажи за свои
words it's yours it can't not your
слова это твоя соб не може не Твоя
property everything You're in someone else's
собственность всё Ты на чужой
house
хате
Yes
Да
Cool I caught you it's Someone else's house in
Классно я тебя поймал это Чужая хата в
yours you would
своей ты бы это
take it Someone else's house in a day what kind
Чужая могу через день забрать что у них
of
за
examples do they have
примеры
Hello and you are
Здравствуйте а вы отку
from Rostov But I live in California
с родом из Ростова Но живу в Калифорнии
already 18 years in 2 years will be the
уже 18 лет через 2 года будет
twentieth Ukrainians will comply with the
двадцатое Украинцы будут соблюдать
Treaty No with Denmark no no Ukraine
Договор Нет с з Данией нет нет Украина
look Ukrainians they all make treaties
смотри украинцы они все делают договоры
with Russia to outwit Russia
с Россией чтобы обхитрить России
signed the Budapest memorandum
будапештский меморандум подписали
outwitted And about Denmark
обхитрил А про Данию
on Denmark
на Данию
in general as Ukraine treaty with
вообще как Украины договор с
Denmark with America will Ukraine go to war
Данией с Америкой пойдёт Украина воевать
Why Well and there is a treaty on protection Yes
Зачем Ну а договор есть о защите Да
Ukraine is our state Ukraine is our state
Украина - это наш штат Украина наш штат
and Denmark is our state We control We
и Дания наш штат Мы контролируем Мы
control all of Europe through NATO And
через НАТО контролируем всю Европу Да
also from the fifth years it is the American
ещё от пятых годов это же американская
American army is in Europe yes
Американская армия стоит в Европе да
we we I asked you a direct question I told
мы мы Я тебе задал прямой вопрос я тебе
you I tell you again I am in Ukraine we
я тебе ещё раз говорю мне на Украи мы
NATO Yes we control both Europe and
НАТО Да мы контролируем и Европу и
Ukraine We stood in West Berlin in 1945
Украину Мы в 45м году встали в Западном
and until the nineties ousted the
Берлине да и до девяностых вытеснили
Soviet Union ousted Moscow from
Советский Союз Москву вытеснили из
Eastern Europe
Восточной Европы
Yes you mean you mean occupiers
Да вы значит вы значит оккупанты
occupied Germany Yes we oh we are
оккупировали германи Да мы о мы
occupiers Yes we occupied Germany and
оккупанты Да мы оккупировали Германию и
not only Germany we  hegemon
не только Германию мы гегемон
we are a superpower only earlier yes
мы сверхдержава единственно раньше да
Earlier yes earlier still the Soviet Union could
Раньше е раньше ещ Советский Союз мог с
come across us But we destroyed it in the Cold
нами попадаться Но мы его в холодной
War
войне
Now you have Russia what
уничтожили У вас теперь Россия какой
Russia
России
North You now when you were the Soviet
Север Вы теперь когда вы были советским
Union yes you had everything your own And now
союзом да у вас всё было своё А сейчас у
you even have the Internet phones everything is ours
вас даже интернет телефоны всё наше
American everything is American the secret services are
американское все американски спецслужбы
watching you
за вами следят
rere will not produce anything only
рере ничего не произведёт только доллары
prints dollars everything so look just like
печатает всё так смотри так же как
Israel pagers also yours at any
Израиль пейджера также ваших в любой
time through phones every your
момент можно через телефоны каждое твоё
look every your move through the
смотри каждое твоё движение через
phone the phone is a computer with a
телефон телефон - это компьютер с
transmitter Yes it is tracked by the
передатчиком Да отслеживается
Central Intelligence Agency of the
центральным разведывательно управлении
United States of America Yes you are in the
Соединённых Штатов Америки Да ты как на
palm of your hand Yes you can hear everything in the palm of your hand
ладони Да ты как на ладони всё слышишь
look our American secret services
смотри наши американские спецслужбы
know everything about you Yes On what sites are you on yes
знают всё про тебя Да На каких сайтах ты
On what In short you are there girls like
да На каких Короче ты там девочек типа
looking at everything I know
засматривается всё знаю Да сказать-то
Yes why say well go on then I'll listen
зачем ну говори дальше тогда послушаю
so yeah look we remained a single
так вот да смотри мы остались единой
superpower now China is still trying
сверхдержавой сейчас Китай ещё пробует
like to catch up but for them it is
типа позиции наверстать но у них это
generally harder and Russia  that Russia can't
вообще тяже а Россия что Россия не может
even make its own passenger plane, damn it, ca
свой блин пассажирский самолёт даже
n't even make a tank, can't make an Armata, still
сделать танк не может сделать армату до
Where, where, with a tank,
на Где где на с тан
look,
посмотри
no, but A Your tanks are burning I won't
нет а вот А ваши танки горят не
argue I'll say We We, as a superpower,
спорю я скажу Мы мы как сверхдержава у
not a single soldier has
нас ни один солдат не
died Holding, look, I'll explain We We We are the
погиб держа смотри объясняю Мы Мы
only power that was able to
единственная держава которая смогла
take part of the Russian Federation, they
часть Российской Федерации взяли курскую
entered the Kursk region and everything through our proxies, these are
область зашли и всё через наши прок это
our proxies, we use them like pawns, in short,
наши прокси мы ими как пешками короче
we capture Russia, we destroy the Russian
захватываем Россию уничтожаем российскую
army and that's it, not a single Look, in my
армию и всё ни один Смотри у меня в
California, rockets don't
Калифорнии ракеты не
fly, I wonder Aren't you afraid that tornadoes
летают интересно А ты не боишься что с
will fly to you from Mexico,
Мексики полетят к вам
grandpa Look, I'm telling you, you are being
смерчи дед Смотри я говорю у вас вас
bombed by our American drones, yours are bombing through
бомбят наши американские дроны через
Ukraine, Tatarstan is being bombed by Kazan,
Украину бомбят ваши Татарстан там Казань
Ryazan, the Armed Forces, like, yes, Moscow, even St. Petersburg, all
Рязань ВС типа да Москву даже Питер все
yours, yours or Ukrainians, ours Well, what do we mean,
ваши ваши или украинские наши Ну мы что
Ukraine doesn't produce anything They're
Украина ничего не производит Они же
just a damn fragment, an appendage of the West, we
просто блин осколок придаток Запада мы
give them drones, our specialists launch them
даём им дроны наши специалисты запускают
under the guise of Ukrainians and that's it I'm telling
под видом украинцев и всё я те говор
you, Trump will punish you for this, you're the same to us
тебя Трамп накажет за это ты поже нам
all  look at us yes we don't have drones
всем смотри у нас да у нас дроны не
flying in California yes
летают в Калифорнии да
[laughter]
[смех]
write on y Instagram I don't know what
пись на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого
it's for you for what else you can watch on
це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись на
my face But for you it's one two
оцей мий фейс Але для тебе це один два
or three clicks But you try me and I
або три клика Але ты тримае мене и я
'll say Wow I have a bunch of fouls and
буду казати Вау в мене там Купа фолов и
I'll have a great mood to do
в мене буде класный настрий щоб робити
but cool video write on y Instagram popk
но крут вдео пись на й Instagram попк
Andriy that's
Андрий вот
it come on I'm waiting for you
так давай я тебя чекаю